Register of the Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Dublin, Ireland) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Dublin, Ireland) records,
1921-1957
59027
Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Dublin, Ireland)
24 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize boxes (11.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, dispatches, memoranda, press releases, financial records, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to Polish-Irish relations, Polish citizens and consular affairs in Ireland, activities of the Polish Government-in-Exile during World War II, and postwar Polish émigrés and émigré affairs. A digital copy of this entire collection is available at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/37/0/-/.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat to find the full extent of the collection.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on microfilm (27 reels).
Digital copy in Poland's National Digital Archive at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/37/0/-/. It was digitized from microfilm by the Polish State Archives.
Historical Note
Polish consulate general in Dublin.
Scope and Content Note
The Polish Consulate in Dublin opened in 1929 as one of the first foreign representations to the young Irish state. For most of the time, it was staffed only by Consul Waclaw Tadeusz Dobrzynski (between 1930 and 1942 he was the consulate's sole employee). Because of stringent economic restrictions imposed by the Polish Foreign Ministry, the post's activities were suspended in 1932 and Dobrzynski, a man of independent means, was appointed Honorary Consul without financial support from Warsaw. After Ireland became a sovereign state in 1937, the status of the post changed to Consulate General.
Dobrzynski's full reinstatement as Consul General occurred later in 1940, under Foreign Minister August Zaleski, with plans for upgrading the consulate to embassy. The staff increased in 1942 when Xavier Zaleski was appointed Press Bureau Chief. The office gradually assumed more diplomatic responsibilities and remained in full operation during World War II. When the conflict ended, Dobrzynski turned down an offer from the communist government in Warsaw to represent it in Ireland, but continued to serve as Consul General until 1954 (though he was paid his last salary in 1948). Out of the former network of 148 diplomatic representations, the Consulate General in Dublin was one of the last three active ones, along with those in Lisbon and at the Vatican.
Even though it played a significant role during its existence, especially during the war, not much evidence of its importance is found in these records, which relate mostly to the usual consular activities. There is some material on Polish-Irish relations, but none on the communication channels Poles were able to maintain with the Axis in matters of mutual interest, thanks to the fact that the Irish remained strictly neutral for the duration of the conflict. (Traces of those channels can be found among the correspondence in the records of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, mentioned below.)
The documents relating to the post-war years chronicle the further disintegration of the Polish diplomatic system struggling to stay alive but running out of funds. On July 5, 1945, the British recognized the communists in Warsaw and the Polish government in London ceased to function legally. Abandoned by the Allies, the Polish administration remaining in the West was faced with the choice of surrendering to the communists or continuing against all odds. There was talk in the press and moves were made to test the ground for a possible transfer of the seat of the government-in-exile to Dublin, but nothing came of it.
From then on, what really mattered to the consular staff was not politics but assistance to former soldiers and refugees to regain their status of normal citizens. The staff issued confirmations of citizenship, birth and marriage certificates, affidavits, demobilization papers, testimonials, etc. Hundreds of documents were processed every day, above all passports, which were recognized by most countries (though not by Great Britain) and served as proof that the holder didn't come from a Soviet-controlled part of Europe.
The Irish, more out of principle than national interest, helped Poles to preserve a sense of dignity, but also advised the Consul General to avoid unnecessary provocation where his influential counterparts was concerned. When Dobrzynski resigned in January 1954, at the age of 71, he was replaced by Zofia Zaleska, and shortly afterwards by Pawel Czerwinski. The office officially closed in March 1958, and provisional diplomatic relations with communist Poland were established by Ireland in 1976.
From 1940 on, the Consulate served as the repository for the archives of the Foreign Ministry. Besides the shortage of space in London, the heavy bombing constituted a grave threat to the safety of the records. In addition, Poles increasingly distrusted the British government, which they found much too accommodating to Soviet demands; the neutral state of Ireland provided the necessary security conditions. Nevertheless, the staff found it increasingly difficult to deal with the size of incoming materials--annual installments shipped from London across the Irish Sea at the beginning of each new year. It is not surprising, therefore, that as early as 1943 the idea of shipping them farther across the ocean emerged, with the Hoover Library (as it was then called) as the final recipient.
The records of the Consulate General in Dublin were eventually acquired by the Hoover Archives in 1959 as part of the Foreign Ministry collection, and were accessioned in the early 1990s as a separate collection. Its classification system is the same as that of the Ministry, established in the 1930s and consisting of 900 index numbers, 200 of which were left blank, available to be used for additional topics, which is in fact what happened during the war. Of course, not all 900 are always used: the records of the Consulate General in Dublin (which, incidentally, was the last to follow the old pattern) cover only about hundred of them.
For a complete listing of the numbers in that classification system, please consult the series list of the register to the "Poland. Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych" records.
A microfilm copy of these materials has been deposited in the State Archives of Poland in Warsaw.
For further study on the affairs of the Consulate General in Dublin, the researcher is advised to contact the Sikorski Institute in London, which, in 1981, acquired over twelve feet of material entitled "The Polish Consulate-General in Dublin," covering the period of 1940-1945, and consisting mostly of approximately 2000 personal files.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Ireland--Foreign relations--Poland.; Poles--Ireland.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; Poland--History--Occupation, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Governments in exile.; Poland.; Ireland.; Great Britain.; World War, 1939-1945.; Poland--Foreign relations--Ireland.
Container List
- SERIES NO. 1. POLITICAL RELATIONS BETWEEN VARIOUS COUNTRIES/NOT INVOLVING POLAND/ (Box 1)
  - 1921 - Irish-British relations. (Folder 1: 1)
    Official correspondence relating to the peace negotiations, 1921 June- September, Dublin, 1921
  - 1932 - "Constitutional Development: Part 2." Unknown author. (Folder 1: 2)
    Typescript with handwritten corrections
  - 1933 - "The Treaty with Great Britain." (Folder 1: 3)
    Typescript
  - 1940-1943 British - Soviet relations. (Folder 1: 4)
    Clippings
  - 1943 - Czechoslovak-Soviet relations. (Folder 1: 5)
- SERIES NO. 3. POLITICAL REPORTS.
  Clippings from Polish émigré press
  - 1940 - Great Britain (Folder 1: 6)
  - 1940-1941 - Allied governments (Folder 1: 7)
  - 1940-1943 - German propaganda abroad (Folder 1: 8)
  - 1941 - Great Britain (Folder 1: 9)
  - 1941-1943 - Lithuania (Folder 1: 10)
  - 1942
    - Allied governments (Folder 1: 11)
    - Great Britain (Folder 1: 12)
  - 1943 - Allied governments (Folder 1: 13)
- SERIES NO. 7. POLITICAL SYSTEM, GOVERNMENT, PARLIAMENT
  - 1929 (Folder 1: 14)
  - 1929-1930 - Imperial conference (Folder 1: 15)
  - 1930 (Folder 1: 16)
  - 1931 (Folder 1: 17)
- SERIES NO. 12. COMMUNIST MOVEMENTS. Komintern, 1943. (Folder 1: 18)
- SERIES NO. 13. MINORITIES OUTSIDE POLAND'S BORDERS.
  - 1940 - German minority in Romania (Folder 1: 19)
  - 1942-1943 - Germans abroad (Folder 1: 20)
  - 1943 - Russian émigré circles (Folder 1: 21)
- SERIES NO. 29. SOCIAL ISSUES (Box 2)
  - 1948 - Health and welfare (Folder 2: 1)
  - 1951 - Ireland's cultural relations, 1950-1951 (Folder 2: 2)
- SERIES NO. 39. ECONOMIC REPORTS
  - 1929 (Folder 2: 3)
  - 1930 (Folder 2: 4)
  - 1931 (Folder 2: 5)
- SERIES NO. 48. INSTRUCTIONS OF MINISTRY. Polish Consul to Ireland. Notes with instructions on ministerial policy. Manuscript, 1950 (Folder 2: 6)
- SERIES NO. 49. POLITICAL RELATIONS WITH POLAND IN GENERAL
  - 1929 - City of Wilno loans (Folder 2: 7)
  - 1940 - Polish-Czechoslovak relations. (Folder 2: 8)
  - 1941
    - Poland's borders. (Folder 2: 9)
    - Polish-Czechoslovak relations.
      - General (Folder 2: 10)
      - Cultural relations (Folder 2: 11)
  - 1942
    - Czechoslovak-Polish Confederation (Proposed) (Folder 2: 12)
    - Czechoslovakia's relations with Poland and other countries (Folder 2: 13)
    - Poland's borders (Folder 2: 14)
    - Polish-Soviet relations. Ministerial communique. (Folder 2: 15)
      Typescript, holograph and mimeograph
  - 1943
    - Central European Federation (Folder 2: 16)
    - Czechoslovak-Polish Confederation (Proposed) (Folder 2: 17)
    - Czechoslovakia's relations with Poland and other countries (Folder 2: 18)
    - Poland's borders (Folder 2: 19)
    - Polish-Soviet relations
      - General
        - General (Folder 2: 20)
        - Annexation of Eastern Poland by the USSR (Folder 2: 21)
        - Polish - Soviet relations 1918 - 1943, Washington, 1943 (Folder 2: 22)
        - Ziemie Wschodnie Polski, London, 1943 (Folder 2: 23)
      - Chronology of Polish - Soviet relations 1941-1943 (Folder 2: 24)
  - 1944 - Polish-Soviet relations - Border issues
    - General (Folder 2: 25)
    - Lwow and South-Eastern Poland (Folder 2: 26)
    - The Western Borderlands of the USSR (Folder 2: 27)
  - 1946 - Biuletyn Informacyjny, no. 73. (Folder 2: 28)
    Includes: "The Responsibility of Soviet-Russia in Germany's Aggression on Poland"
- SERIES NO. 53. NAME INDEX (INSTRUCTIONS). Diplomatic and consular representatives at Consulate in Dublin, 1941 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- SERIES NO. 54. MARITIME AFFAIRS. Polish maritime law (Folder 3: 2)
- SERIES NO. 57. ECONOMIC RELATIONS WITH POLAND IN GENERAL, 1929-1931 (Folder 3: 3)
- SERIES NO. 57/A. EXPORT POSSIBILITIES OF POLISH GOODS
  - 1929-1931
    - General (Folder 3: 4)
    - Hops (Folder 3: 5)
    - Lumber (Folder 3: 6)
  - 1931 - Clothing (Folder 3: 7)
- SERIES NO. 57/B. CLEARING TRADE. Ireland-Poland, 1931 (Folder 3: 8)
- SERIES NO. 60. CERTIFICATE OF PRODUCT ORIGIN, 1929-1930 (Folder 3: 9)
- SERIES NO. 70. ECONOMIC CONDITIONS IN POLAND.
  News summaries
  - 1929 (Folder 3: 10)
  - 1929-1930 (Folder 3: 11)
  - 1932 (Folder 3: 12)
  - 1933 (Folder 3: 13)
- SERIES NO. 71. ECONOMIC CONDITIONS IN POLAND. Craftsmanship, 1940-1943 (Folder 3: 14)
- SERIES NO. 73. POLITICAL CONDITIONS IN POLAND
  - 1940 - Arrests of Jagiellonian University professors. (Folder 3: 15)
    Protest note
  - 1941 - Persecution of church. (Folder 3: 16)
- SERIES NO. 73/A. GERMAN OCCUPATION ZONE.
  - 1941
    - German policy toward Poland (Folder 3: 17)
    - German racial policy (Folder 3: 18)
  - 1941-1943
    - Taxation of Polish population (Folder 3: 19)
    - Women, Fate of (Folder 3: 20)
  - 1942
    - German policy toward Poland (Folder 3: 21)
    - Persecution of church (Folder 3: 22)
  - 1942-1943 - German state employees (Folder 3: 23)
  - 1943
    - German policy toward Poland (Folder 3: 24)
    - Persecution of church (Folder 3: 25)
- SERIES NO. 89. LIQUIDATION AGREEMENT. Inquiries about individuals (Box 4)
  - 1942 (Folder 4: 1)
  - 1943 (Folder 4: 2)
  - 1945 (Folder 4: 3)
- SERIES NO. 122. VATICAN'S RELATIONS WITH POLAND
  - 1942 - Vatican's assistance to Polish refugees (Folder 4: 4)
  - 1943 - Vatican's assistance to Polish refugees (Folder 4: 5)
  - 1947 - Polish-Vatican relations (Folder 4: 6)
- SERIES NO. 164. REPATRIATION. INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS OF REFUGEE ASSISTANCE, 1946
  - Arrival of Polish children in Ireland (Folder 4: 7)
  - Vatican's aid to Polish children and students (Folder 4: 8)
- SERIES NO. 184. INTERNATIONAL CONGRESSES, CONFERENCES AND MEETINGS. International Eucharistic Congress, 1929-1930 (Folder 4: 9)
- SERIES NO. 191. RELATIONS BETWEEN SCHOLARLY INSTITUTIONS. Association of Architects, 1930 (Folder 4: 10)
- SERIES NO. 236. PANEUROPE. European Union. Polish government response to French initiative, 1930 (Folder 4: 11)
- SERIES NO. 245. WAR OF 1939 AND POSTWAR PLANNING
  - 1939 - Broadcast of Ambassador Raczynski from September 9 (Folder 4: 12)
  - 1940-1943 (Folder 4: 13)
  - 1941
    - General.
      - May (Folder 4: 14)
      - June (Folder 4: 15)
      - July (Folder 4: 16)
      - August (Folder 4: 17)
      - September (Folder 4: 18)
      - October (Folder 4: 19)
    - Underground, Activities of. (Folder 4: 20)
  - 1942
    - General.
      - January (Folder 4: 21)
      - February (Folder 4: 22)
      - March-April (Folder 4: 23)
      - May-June (Folder 4: 24)
      - July (Folder 4: 25)
      - August-September (Folder 4: 26)
      - October-December (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Underground, Activities of. (Folder 5: 2)
  - 1943
    - General
      - January (Folder 5: 3)
      - February (Folder 5: 4)
      - March-April (Folder 5: 5)
      - May (Folder 5: 6)
      - June (Folder 5: 7)
      - July-December (Folder 5: 8)
    - Underground activities (Folder 5: 9)
- SERIES NO. 245/4. WAR ATROCITIES
  - 1940-1941. (Folder 5: 10)
  - 1942. (Folder 5: 11)
  - 1943
    - General. (Folder 5: 12)
    - "Zagadnienie karania przestepcow wojennych." (Folder 5: 13)
      Mimeograph
  - 1946 - Poland Accuses: An Indictment of the Major German War Criminals, London, 1946 (Folder 5: 14)
- SERIES NO. 245/7. REFUGEES. Polish refugees (Box 6)
  - 1948 (Folder 6: 1)
  - 1949 (Folder 6: 2)
  - 1950 (Folder 6: 3)
  - 1951 (Folder 6: 4)
- SERIES NO. 245/9. ORGANIZATION OF POSTWAR WORLD
  - 1940-1941. (Folder 6: 5)
  - 1942
    - General. (Folder 6: 6)
    - American approach (Folder 6: 7)
    - President, Polish (Folder 6: 8)
  - 1943. (Folder 6: 9)
  - 1944 - Ministerstwo Spraw Kongresowych (Ministry of Postwar Planning) (Folder 6: 10)
- SERIES NO. 251. POLISH LEGISLATION AND CHURCH. Catholic Church in Poland, Persecution of (Folder 6: 11)
- SERIES NO. 276. CULTURAL AFFAIRS OF EMIGRES
  - 1930 - Polish schools, 25th anniversary (Folder 6: 12)
  - 1931 - Polish schools, 25th anniversary (Folder 6: 13)
  - 1940 - Ethical conduct of Polish political emigrants. (Folder 6: 14)
- SERIES NO. 277. POLISH YOUTH STUDYING ABROAD
  - 1945
    - General (Folder 6: 15)
    - Ireland (Folder 6: 16)
  - 1946 - Ireland (Folder 6: 17)
  - 1952-1957 (Folder 6: 18)
- SERIES NO. 298. POLISH SCHOOL SYSTEM ABROAD. ORGANIZATION, PERSONNEL. Polski Uniwersytet na Obczyznie. Szkola Nauk Politycznych i Spolecznych, 1955 (Folder 6: 19)
- SERIES NO. 304. POLISH CHURCH ABROAD. Polish Mission in Shuntehfu, China. Report on martyrdrom of Kazimierz Skowyra, 1947 (Box-folder 7: 1)
- SERIES NO. 312. WAR REFUGEES
  - 1946-1948 - Welfare recipients (Folder 7: 2)
  - 1948
    - East Africa-Tangier. List of orphans (76) (Folder 7: 3)
    - Sweden. List of refugees from Germany (75) (Folder 7: 4)
- SERIES NO. 315. INFORMATION ON EMIGRATION MATTERS
  - 1937 - Edmund Strzelecki anniversary (Folder 7: 5)
  - 1940 (Folder 7: 6)
  - 1941 (Folder 7: 7)
  - 1942 (Folder 7: 8)
  - 1943 (Folder 7: 9)
- SERIES NO. 317. ORGANIZATION OF PRESS SERVICES. PLANS AND INSTRUCTIONS
  - 1929-1931. (Folder 7: 10)
    Annual report
  - 1930. (Folder 7: 11)
    Instructions
- SERIES NO. 323/A. PRESS REPORTS. Periodical reports on Irish press, 1929-1930 (Folder 7: 12)
- SERIES NO. 323/B. FOREIGN JOURNALISTS. Clippings, 1940-1943 (Folder 7: 13)
- SERIES NO. 324/A. POLISH PRESS AGENCIES, 1931
  - General (Folder 7: 14)
  - Bulletins (Folder 7: 15)
  - Correspondence from Consulate in Dublin (Folder 7: 16)
  - Instructions (Folder 7: 17)
  - List of foreign correspondents (Folder 7: 18)
- SERIES NO. 330/A. COMMUNIQUES, TELEGRAMS, ARTICLES, BULLETINS FOR POLISH PRESS
  - 1930 (Folder 7: 19)
  - 1931 (Box 8)
    - Gdansk, Anti-Polish acts in (Folder 8: 1)
    - Germany, Anti-Polish acts in (Folder 8: 2)
    - Polish-Soviet war, Anniversary of (Folder 8: 3)
    - Ukrainians
      - Chomyszyn, Grzegorz on social conditions of Ukrainians in Poland (Folder 8: 4)
      - Pacification of (Folder 8: 5)
    - Upper Silesian economy (Folder 8: 6)
- SERIES NO. 330/B. COMMUNIQUES, TELEGRAMS, ARTICLES, BULLETINS FOR FOREIGN PRESS
  - 1930
    - General. Circular (Folder 8: 7)
    - Irish press (Folder 8: 8)
  - 1932 (Folder 8: 9)
  - 1933 (Folder 8: 10)
- SERIES NO. 332. PUBLICITY IN LITERATURE, ARTS, MUSIC, THEATER, OPERA, BALLET, NATIONAL COSTUMES
  - 1929
    - Music (Folder 8: 11)
    - Phillips, Alison, Lecturer (Folder 8: 12)
  - 1930 - Theater (Folder 8: 13)
- SERIES NO. 333. PUBLICITY IN FILM, SLIDES AND PHOTOGRAPHY, 1929-1931 (Folder 8: 14)
- SERIES NO. 335. PUBLICITY IN SPORT
  - 1929-1930 (Folder 8: 15)
  - 1931 (Folder 8: 16)
- SERIES NO. 336. LECTURES
  - 1930 (Folder 8: 17)
  - 1941 (Folder 8: 18)
  - 1942 (Folder 8: 19)
  - 1943 (Folder 8: 20)
- SERIES NO. 337. CELEBRATIONS AND COMMEMORATIONS, 1956. Jan Kazimierz oath, 300th anniversary of (Folder 8: 21)
- SERIES NO. 338. FAIRS
  - 1929 - Powszechna Wystawa Krajowa Poznan (Folder 8: 22)
  - 1929-1931
    - Miedzynarodowe Targi Wschodnie (Folder 8: 23)
    - Targi Miedzynarodowe Poznan (Folder 8: 24)
- SERIES NO. 341. PUBLICATIONS (Box 9)
  - 1941 - Propaganda
    - General
      - January-April (Folder 9: 1)
      - May-August (Folder 9: 2)
      - September-December (Folder 9: 3)
    - Talbot Press (Folder 9: 4)
  - 1942
    - General
      - January-April (Folder 9: 5)
      - May-August (Folder 9: 6)
      - September-December (Folder 9: 7)
    - Talbot Press (Folder 9: 8)
  - 1943
    - General
      - General (Folder 9: 9)
      - January-April (Folder 9: 10)
      - May-August (Folder 9: 11)
      - September-December (Folder 9: 12)
    - Talbot Press (Folder 9: 13)
  - 1944
    - General
      - General (Folder 9: 14)
      - January-April (Folder 9: 15)
      - May-August (Folder 9: 16)
    - Talbot Press (Folder 9: 17)
  - 1945 (Folder 9: 18)
  - 1945-1946 (Folder 9: 19)
  - 1947 (Folder 9: 20)
  - 1949 - Protest Wolnych Ludzi w Sprawie Polski, London (Folder 9: 21)
  - 1953-1955 - Matka Boska Kozielska (Folder 9: 22)
  - 1953-1957 (Folder 9: 23)
- SERIES NO. 348. TRIPS, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 10: 1)
- SERIES NO. 359/D. LEGISLATURE, CONGRESSES, CONFERENCES, INTERNATIONAL MEETINGS. AERIAL TRANSPORTATION. Conference on Private Aerial Law, 1929 (Folder 10: 2)
- SERIES NO. 365/B. RAILROADS, FOREIGN. Fares, 1930 (Folder 10: 3)
- SERIES NO. 367. NAVIGATION
  - 1940. (Folder 10: 4)
  - 1941
    - General (Folder 10: 5)
    - Clippings (Folder 10: 6)
  - 1942. (Folder 10: 7)
  - 1943. (Folder 10: 8)
- SERIES NO. 367/A. SEA NAVIGATION
  - 1940 (Folder 10: 9)
  - 1941 (Folder 10: 10)
  - 1942 (Folder 10: 11)
  - 1943 (Folder 10: 12)
- SERIES NO. 406. RECOMMENDATION LETTERS AND CERTIFICATES. Certificates, 1946-1947 (Folder 10: 13)
- SERIES NO. 408. MINISTRY'S INFORMATION BULLETINS
  - 1930
    - August-October (Folder 10: 14)
    - November-December (Folder 10: 15)
  - 1933 - Polish Press Information Bulletin (Folder 10: 16)
- SERIES NO. 410. TELEGRAMS BETWEEN MINISTRY AND POLAND'S FOREIGN REPRESENTATIONS
  - 1929-1931
    - General (Folder 10: 17)
    - Dublin - Foreign consulates (Folder 10: 18)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 10: 19)
  - 1932
    - General (Folder 10: 20)
    - Dublin - Foreign consulates (Folder 10: 21)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 10: 22)
  - 1940 (Folder 10: 23)
  - 1941 (Box 11)
    - General (Folder 11: 1)
    - Dublin
      - Catholic authorities (Folder 11: 2)
      - Foreign consulates (Folder 11: 3)
      - Foreign legations (Folder 11: 4)
    - Ireland
      - Department of Defense (Folder 11: 5)
      - Department of External Affairs (Folder 11: 6)
    - Poland - London offices
      - Consulate (Folder 11: 7)
      - Embassy (Folder 11: 8)
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Ministerstwo Spraw Zagranicznych)
        - January-February
          - General (Folder 11: 9)
          - Ireland's internal situation and possibility of invasion (Folder 11: 10)
        - March-April (Folder 11: 11)
        - May-June (Folder 11: 12)
        - July-August
          - General (Folder 11: 13)
          - Polish-Soviet agreement (Folder 11: 14)
        - September-October (Folder 11: 15)
        - November-December (Folder 11: 16)
  - 1942
    - General (Folder 11: 17)
    - Dublin - Foreign consulates (Folder 11: 18)
    - Ireland
      - Department of External Affairs
        - General (Folder 11: 19)
        - German war crimes. Polish government protest note, June (Folder 11: 20)
    - Poland
      - Consulate, London (Folder 11: 21)
      - Embassy, London (Folder 11: 22)
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Box 12)
        - January-February
          - General (Folder 12: 1)
          - Extermination of Jews (Folder 12: 2)
        - March-April (Folder 12: 3)
        - May-June
          - General (Folder 12: 4)
          - German war atrocities. Government protest (Folder 12: 5)
        - July-August (Folder 12: 6)
        - September-October
          - General (Folder 12: 7)
          - Poland's western borders. Ministry's instruction (Folder 12: 8)
        - November-December
          - General (Folder 12: 9)
          - Bank Polski - Reorganization in occupied Poland (Folder 12: 10)
          - MacRory, Cardinal - Gray, David (Folder 12: 11)
          - Polish war aims (Folder 12: 12)
  - 1943
    - General (Folder 12: 13)
    - Dublin - Foreign consulates (Folder 12: 14)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs. (Folder 12: 15)
      Includes protest notes on German extermination policies
    - Poland
      - Consulate, London (Folder 12: 16)
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
        - January-February (Folder 12: 17)
        - March-April (Folder 12: 18)
        - May-June
          - General (Folder 12: 19)
          - Pius XII, Speech of June 2 (Folder 12: 20)
        - July-August (Folder 12: 21)
        - September-October (Folder 13: 1)
        - November-December (Folder 13: 2)
  - 1944
    - General (Folder 13: 3)
    - Ireland. Department of External Affairs (Folder 13: 4)
    - Poland
      - Consulate, London (Folder 13: 5)
      - Embassy, London (Folder 13: 6)
      - Ministry of Foreign Affairs
        - January-February (Folder 13: 7)
        - March-April (Folder 13: 8)
        - May-June
          - General (Folder 13: 9)
          - Postwar world order (Folder 13: 10)
        - July-August
          - General (Folder 13: 11)
          - Clippings (Folder 13: 12)
        - September-October
          - General (Folder 13: 13)
          - Gawlina, Jozef. Pastoral letter to Poles in Russia from October 29 (Folder 13: 14)